# KEISHA CARD

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**1** 615-419-9406

X CARDKEISHA@GMAIL.COM

WWW.GITHUB.COM/KEISHACARD

in LINKEDIN.COM/IN/KEISHA-CARD

WWW.KEISHACARD.COM

#### PROFILE

As an experienced nurse, becoming knowledgeable about different electronic charting software and data collection software, like EPIC and REDCap, sparked an interest in software development that makes a positive impact in healthcare. My goal is to be that bridge between healthcare teams and developers in creating meaningful software.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### GREENHAND GARDENER

- Single page application for new gardeners who want to create a fun, functional garden but don't know where to start
- User chooses between garden themes which contain preselected plants and growing tips
- Full CRUD functionality
- Technologies used: JavaScript, ReactApp, ReactStrap, JSON server, CSS

Link: https://github.com/keishacard/gree nhand-gardener

#### TRESTLEBRIDGE FARM

- Refactoring group exercise
- Console application for building a farm, purchasing livestock and crops, tracking capacity of fields and facilities, displaying farm status
- Technologies used: C#/.NET, LINQ query syntax

Link: https://github.com/bearsplosion/Trestlebridge-Farms

# EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | 2019 FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

B.S, NURSING | 2010-2013
LONG ISLAND UNIVERSITY

EXPERIENCE

#### **NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | APRIL 2019 - SEPT 2019

HTML

css

**JAVASCRIPT** 

C# .NET

SQL

Six month full stack bootcamp for C#, .NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React:

- Building browser-based single page applications utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, third-party APIs
- Using C#/.NET, LINQ query syntax for console applications
- Implementing source code version control utilizing Git
- Project management and issue tracking with GitHub Projects, Trello, and ER diagrams

#### **GROUP PROJECTS:**

- WELCOME TO NASHVILLE: Single page application for user visiting
  Nashville to build a trip itinerary utilizing Grunt, JSON, CSS, and vanilla
  JavaScript. Personally responsible for building feature that accessed
  Nashville's Metro Parks API to search for, display and add selected local
  parks to user's itinerary.
- NUTSHELL: Single page app for social network utilizing React, HTML, CSS, Javascript. Personally responsible for building CRUD functionality of task list feature and contributed to events feature.

# **VANDERBILT UNIVERSITY MEDICAL CENTER 2014 - PRESENT**

ACUTE DIALYSIS AND APHERESIS RN II | 2018 - PRESENT ACUTE DIALYSIS AND APHERESIS RN I | 2014 - 2016

- · Promoted from RN I to RN II
- Perform apheresis and hemodialysis treatments in adults and pediatrics
- Utilize EPIC and Vanderbilt proprietary software
- Cannulate vascular accesses: fistulas, grafts, CVCs, and implanted ports
- Serve as highly engaged, adaptable, full partner on team; assisting team
  members as needed; participating in environment of open dialogue, inquiry,
  and continuous development by responding to feedback and improving
  practice
- Effectively apply evidence-based nursing practice, cultural intelligence, and the nursing process to meet patients' needs

# CLINICAL RESEARCH NURSE SPECIALIST RN | 2016-2018

- Research nurse on team conducting proof-of-concept studies and clinical trials on autonomic- neurogenic-disorders, and identifying genetic markers that may link blood lipid concentrations and metabolic diseases
- · Utilized EPIC, REDCap, Excel, and Vanderbilt proprietary software
- Coordinated research projects in adherence to protocol requirements, including completing and communicating regulatory documents, developing data capture, reporting adverse events, contributing to findings in collaboration with researchers for eventual publication
- Served as liaison between investigators, researchers, and administration, to assist in protocol development, informed consent, enrollment/retention of participants, safety maintenance

# UNITED BLOOD SYSTEMS | 2013 - 2014

ACUTE APHERESIS NURSE

 Performed apheresis and hemodialysis treatments in adult and pediatric acute and critical care populations